hi everyone its Rendon with TJ free and
大家好 我是Rendon TJ免费的
in this video we're going to be using
在这段视频中 我们将使用
shot cut to create some highlighted
快照剪辑以创建一些高亮显示
areas or rather we're going to make
或者更确切地说 我们将使
parts of the video dark and then mask
视频的某些部分变暗 然后遮罩
out the part that we want to draw
把我们要画的部分画出来
attention to so we're going to be using
请注意 我们将使用
masking and first we need to find a part
首先 我们需要找到一个部件
of this video that we want to I'll just
我们想要的这段视频我只想
come to a part that we want to highlight
来到我们想要突出显示的部分
so maybe selecting this tool right here
所以也许在这里选择这个工具
is a good place selecting the text tool
是选择文本工具的好地方
instead of having everything be visible
而不是让所有的东西都可见
and it's kind of hard to see the mouse
而且很难看到老鼠
right there we can highlight that so I'm
就在那里 我们可以突出显示它 所以我
going to come up here and get a second
我要到这里来 给我一秒钟
video track I'll right click and go to
我将右键单击并转到视频曲目
add video track and then I'm going to go
添加视频曲目 然后我要走了
open other and go to color and I'm just
打开其他的 去上色 我只是
gonna keep this as it says transparent
我会像它所说的那样保持透明
right now I'll change the color to a
现在我要将颜色更改为
black and go to actually we can do it
黑色和去实际上我们可以做到
opacity maybe I should do that let's do
不透明 也许我应该这么做 我们开始吧
this one right here if we can and go to
如果我们可以的话 这个就在这里
select
选择
I haven't tried the okay doesn't do
我还没试过OK Do Not呢
opacity so this is just black that looks
不透明 所以这只是黑色 看起来
like but what we're gonna do we're gonna
就像但我们要做的是
go into we're gonna drag this down to
进入 我们将把这件事拖到
the timeline first and then we'll select
首先是时间线 然后我们将选择
it oh it did do opacity okay great so
它哦 它确实做到了不透明 好的 很好
this is already it has some opacity if
这是它已经有一些不透明 如果
it didn't there's a filter called
它不是有一个过滤器叫
opacity we could add and we just add
我们可以添加不透明度 我们只需添加
opacity and then we can change the
不透明度 然后我们可以更改
amount of opacity we want that put into
我们希望放入的不透明度大小
this but this is actually less steps so
这个 但这实际上是更少的步骤
we're not going to apply opacity you can
我们不会应用不透明度 您可以
see it's already it's already made it so
看 它已经是 它已经是这样了
that we can kind of see through but it's
我们可以看穿它 但它是
darker and now we're going to add in a
更暗 现在我们要添加一个
mask so we'll go back to the beginning
戴上面具 让我们回到起点
of the clip here and we'll go to filters
在这里 我们将转到过滤器
and go to add and then we'll just search
然后转到添加 然后我们只需搜索
for masks and there's a couple different
对于面具 有几个不同的
ones but we're gonna do masks a simple
但是我们要做一个简单的面具
shape because we're gonna do a rectangle
形状 因为我们要做一个矩形
and that creates this black rectangle so
这就产生了这个黑色矩形 所以
what we need to do is I'm gonna come in
我们要做的是我要进来
here so we can see it a little bit
在这里 我们可以稍微看一下
better
更好的
we click on the clip and then we come
我们点击剪辑 然后我们就来了
over here to these settings and we can
在这里到这些设置 我们可以
change the location of it so we change
更改它的位置 这样我们就可以更改
horizontal and vertical until this is
水平和垂直 直到这是
right over top of the tool that we want
就在我们想要的工具上面
and then we change the size the width
然后我们改变宽度的大小
and height over here so that it's kind
和高度在这里 所以它是友好的
of smaller and you're seeing the problem
你看到了问题所在
of course is that it's covering up what
当然 它掩盖了
we want to see instead of exposing it so
我们想看看 而不是这样曝光
we changed this operation
我们改变了这次行动
from over right to subtract and then it
从右边到减法 然后它
shows the transparent background in
显示中的透明背景
there and it also shows this and we can
它还显示了这一点 我们可以
fine tune if you use your scroll wheel
如果您使用滚轮 则可以进行微调
over top of the bar it makes really
在酒吧的顶端 它真的让人
large adjustments oh that's rotation we
大的调整哦 那是轮换
can reset that back to zero by clicking
可以通过单击将其重置为零
there but if we go back to width if we
但如果我们回到宽度 如果我们
hover over and use our mouse wheel over
将鼠标悬停在上方并使用鼠标滚轮
top of the numbers with a percentage
位居榜首的是一个百分比
it'll do a much more fine adjustment so
它会做更细微的调整 所以
I can finally come in here and I could
我终于可以进来了 我可以
type it in too but I'll just quickly get
也输入它 但我很快就会得到
this right to the place that I want you
这就是我想要你去的地方
didn't hear my squeaky mouse wheel and
没有听到我吱吱作响的鼠标滚轮的声音
maybe that's about good right there and
也许这就是好消息
then what we can do is we can apply a
然后我们可以做的就是将一个
fade so right now if we play this it'll
所以现在如果我们玩这个 它就会消失
look like this it just cuts over to that
看起来像这样 它就这样切到了那个
tool and we can move it so I'll move
工具 我们可以移动它 所以我也会移动
this up a little bit we'll move this
这个再往上一点 我们要把这个移到
back and I can play no cut to that I can
回来 我可以打不到我能打到的位置
I can left-click and hold and move this
我可以左键点击并按住并移动它
back and we can make it longer make it
回来 我们可以让它变得更长
display longer to if we want to the
如果我们想要显示更长的时间
whole thing that's pretty good and now
整件事都很好 现在
we can apply a fade and there's a couple
我们可以应用淡入淡出 然后有几个
ways to do that we could just click on
要做到这一点 我们只需点击
the clip and go into filters and add a
剪辑并进入滤镜 然后添加一个
fade if we wanted to a video fade or we
淡入淡出如果我们想要淡出视频 或者我们
can just if I get out of this we can
如果我离开这里 我们能不能
just come to the clip and hover over and
只需来到剪辑并将鼠标悬停在
this black circle appears left click and
这个黑色圆圈出现在鼠标左键并单击
hold on that black circle and we can
抓住那个黑圈 我们就能
drag this out as long as we want the
只要我们想要 就把它拖出来
fade to happen at the beginning and then
一开始就淡出 然后
the same thing at the end and that will
在最后做同样的事情 这将是
fade in and out any audio or video
淡入和淡出任何音频或视频
associated with the clip so now it fades
与剪辑相关联 因此现在它会褪色
and then we need to click on the clip
然后我们需要点击剪辑
and go to those fade options we don't
转到那些我们不能选择的淡出选项
need to fade audio because there's no
需要淡入淡出音频 因为没有
audio on this clip but the fade video in
此剪辑上的音频 但淡入的视频
we want to make sure we click this
我们希望确保我们点击此按钮
checkbox adjust opacity instead of a
复选框调整不透明度 而不是
fade instead of fade with black so on
用黑色代替褪色 依此类推
both of them on the fade in and out
他们两个都在淡入淡出
we'll make sure that's checked and now
我们会检查的 现在
it'll look really cool it'll fade in the
它看起来真的很酷 它会在
whole thing just like this and then it
整件事就像这样 然后它
shows it and it's going very slow right
展示了它 它走得很慢 对吧
now
现在
then it'll fade it out so maybe that's
然后它就会淡出 所以也许那是
even too much and then if we want to use
即使太多了 如果我们想要使用
this same effect or this same mask with
这种相同的效果或使用相同的面具
these settings we can just right click
我们只需右键单击这些设置即可
and go to copy
然后转到Copy
and we can go to another location in the
我们可以去世界上另一个地方
video to where we're selecting another
视频到我们正在选择另一个
tool suppose we're selecting a tool over
假设我们正在选择一个工具
here we can come to that location and
在这里 我们可以来到那个地点
just do ctrl V to paste that and now we
只需按Ctrl V键即可粘贴 现在我们
have it pasted over here and if it's a
把它贴在这里 如果它是一个
different tool we can just come over to
不同的工具 我们可以直接使用
this vertical and change where that is
这是垂直的 并改变了它的位置
at on the vertical so we can change that
在垂直方向 所以我们可以改变这一点
we can even come over here and select a
我们甚至可以到这里来 选择一个
tool across the top by changing vertical
通过更改垂直方向来横穿顶部的工具
and horizontal so whatever tool we
所以无论我们用什么工具
happen to be selecting we can just
碰巧我们选择的是
highlight that and it'll show that tool
突出显示该选项 它将显示该工具
and it'll still apply it with the exact
它仍然会将其与完全相同的
same fades and everything and if we've
同样的褪色和一切 如果我们已经
suppose we were doing something over
假设我们在做一件事
here we could even it doesn't have to be
在这里 我们甚至可以不是必须的
just a rectangle so we can come over
只是一个矩形 这样我们就可以过来了
here and change or a square we can
我们可以在这里换衣服 或者换个广场
change the width here to more like a
将此处的宽度更改为更像
rectangular area to cover like a whole
覆盖成一个整体的矩形区域
thing or width and height and we can
东西或宽度和高度 我们可以
come down just like this so this is a
就像这样下来 所以这是一个
really cool feature you can do the same
非常酷的功能 你也可以做同样的事情
thing in kdenlive
kdenlive的事情
and in all kinds of you know all kinds
在各种各样的你知道各种各样的
of different video editors that are
不同的视频编辑器
open-source as well I just thought it's
也是开源的我只是认为它
particularly easy to accomplish this in
特别容易实现这一点
shot cut you can also save these presets
shot Cut您还可以保存这些收件箱
over here like these exact presets if
就像这些一模一样的小丑一样
you want to you can come over here and
你想你可以过来这里
go preset and go add and then you can
进行预设并添加 然后您就可以了
just call this large box or whatever you
就称这个大盒子或任何你
want to call it and then that way if
想打电话然后这样如果
even after you close the program and get
即使您关闭程序并获得
back in you can always come to this
回到这里 你总是可以来到这个
preset so if you change things over to
预先设置 如果您将内容更改为
here and you want that preset of where
在这里 您想要预设位置
it was over there you just come down to
就在那里 你刚刚来到
your large box preset and it sets it up
您的大盒子预设并设置它
exactly how it was so thanks for
到底是怎么样的所以谢谢
watching guys if you have any questions
如果您有任何疑问 请关注大家
or comments leave them below hope you
或评论留在下面希望您
find this video informative and look
发现此视频内容丰富 并查看
forward to catching you in the next
期待在接下来的时间里赶上你
video
视频
you
你